さぁ　君達を ハンター試験会場まで案内しよう。
We will now take you to the exam site.
よかったね ３人一緒に合格できて。
Isn't it great that we all passed?
喜ぶのは　早い。
It's too early to celebrate.
あくまで 受験資格を手にしただけだ。
We've merely earned the right
to take the real exam.
ゴン一行は　ナビゲーター キリコに案内され 試験会場である ここ　ザバン市に到着していた
Gon and his new friends have arrived in Zaban City, site of the Hunter Exam, aided by the Kiriko Navigators.
我々　ナビゲーターは 有能なハンター志望者を見つけ
As Navigators, our job is to identify
worthy Hunter applicants
試験会場まで案内するのが 仕事なのさ。
and guide them to the exam site.
つまり　ナビゲートなしで 試験会場へ　たどり着くのは
In other words, it would be extremely
difficult for someone to reach the site
至難の業ってわけさ。
without a Navigator's help.
さぁ！　１本どうだい！
Hey, wanna try one?
ザバン名物 パンダガエルの姿焼き！
It's Zaban's famous panda-frog-on-a-stick!
絶品だよ！
A true delicacy!
ザバン地下宮殿から 発掘されたブローチ！
This brooch was excavated from
Zaban's underground palace.
国宝級よん！
I bet that it's a national treasure.
しかし　ザバン市って うさんくせぇとこだな。
You know, Zaban City is quite a shady place.
栄えた町には それだけ怪しい奴や 荒くれ者も流れて来る。 うわぁ！
Prosperous cities tend to attract
all sorts of nasty types.
何やってんだ？　ゴン　行くぞ！
What are you doing, Gon? We're going!
うん！
Yeah!
どうやら…
I believe
あそこの建物だな。
that is the building.
へ？
Huh?
高い！　すごく立派な建物だね。
It's so tall! They have a really nice building.
これが試験会場か…。
So this is the exam site...
ここに　世界各地から…。
This is what draws...
ハンター志望の猛者が 集まるわけだな。
Hunter applicants from across the world.
ハンター試験　初挑戦。
My first shot at the Hunter Exam...
親父も こんな気持だったのかな？
Was this how Dad felt, when he first arrived?
君達！ ん？
Hey, guys! Hmm?
こっち　こっち！ えっ？
Over here. What?
ここだよ。
Here.
おいおい　冗談キツいぜ！
Wait, this isn't funny.
どう見たって ただの定食屋じゃねえか！
Isn't that an ordinary restaurant?
まさか　この中に 全世界のハンター志望者が集まる
You can't possibly mean that Hunter
applicants from around the world
…なんて いうんじゃねえだろうな？
are meant to assemble here?
その　まさかさ。 え？
I do. Huh?
ここなら　応募者が 数百万人ともいわれている ハンター試験の会場だとは 誰も思わないだろ？
No one would ever expect the Hunter Exam, with its millions of candidates,
to be located here, right?
確かに…。
That's true.
奥の部屋　空いてる？
Welcome! Is the back room open?
ご注文は？
What will you have?
目からウロコが落ちるような ステーキ定食　３人前。
The steak combo that opens
your eyes to the light. For three.
３人前ね…　焼き方は？
For three... How would you like them?
弱火で　じっくりコトコト 飽きるまで。
Grilled over a low flame, until cooked.
あいよ　奥の部屋どうぞ。
Got it. Let yourself into the back room.
ここで待て。
Wait here.
「待て」って…　他の受験者は？
Wait? Where are the others?
ステーキ定食　楽しみだね！
I can't wait for the steak combo.
ゴン　あれは　この部屋に 通してもらうための　合言葉さ。
Gon, that was just the password
to get us inside.
なんだ　食べられないんだ。
Oh, we don't get to eat?
１万人に１人…。
One in every ten thousand...
ん？
Hmm?
受験応募者が ここに　たどり着くまでの確率さ。
The number of applicants
who make it this far.
君達　新人にしては　上出来だ。
You've done extremely well for first-timers.
じゃあ　頑張ってな。
Well, good luck.
ありがとう！
Thanks!
君達なら 来年も案内してあげるよ。
I would be happy to serve as your
Navigator next year, as well.
何だ？
What?
どうやら　この部屋は エレベーターらしい。
It appears this room is an elevator.
あの野郎 あれじゃ　まるで俺達が
Bastard...
今年は 受からねえみてぇじゃねえか。
That meant that he expects us
to fail this year.
３年に１人だそうだ。 何が？
Once every three years. What's that?
ルーキーが合格する確率だ。 えっ？
The frequency with which a
rookie passes the exam. Huh?
そんなに少ないんだ。
It's that unusual?
中には　テストの過酷さに 心身　共にボロボロになる者
Some cannot endure the exam's physical and mental strain.
ベテラン受験者に　つぶされて
It's also not unusual for veterans
二度とテストを 受けられなくなった者なども ザラらしい。
to break the rookies,
who consequently never retake the test.
そんな大変な目に遭ってまで みんな　ハンターになりたいんだね。
So I guess candidates are willing to risk
everything to become Hunters.
そりゃあ　お前 決まってるじゃねえか！
But of course, my friend!
ハンターは　この世で 最も儲かる仕事なんだぜぇ！
Hunters make the most money in this world!
違う！　ハンターこそ この世で最も気高い仕事なのだ。
No! Hunters are the most noble in this world.
ええカッコしいめ！
Glory hog...
金の亡者め！
Money grubber!
ゴン！　まぁ　聞け！
Gon! Listen...
世界大富豪ランキング ベスト１００には
Every year, over fifty Hunters
毎年　必ず５０人以上のハンターが 名を連ねているんだぜ！
make the list of the world's
hundred richest people!
おっ　おぉ…。 ハンターといえば　動物を狩り 宝をあさるイメージがあるが それは　二流。
Hunters are associated with
hunting wild game and treasure, but they are all second-rate.
人と自然の秩序を守ることこそ ハンターの本当の仕事だ！
True Hunters work to protect
people and the natural order.
いいか　ハンターになりゃ ほとんどの国は　フリーパス！
Now, look here... Once you're a Hunter, most countries
will give you a free pass!
公共施設もタダ！ すんげぇ特権だろ？
And no charge to use public facilities. How are those benefits?
貴重な文化遺産や動植物の保護 指名手配犯や 悪質なハンターの取り締まり ハードだが枢機な仕事なんだ。
Hunters have many difficult and
important responsibilities, such as preserving cultural artifacts
and endangered species, as well as capturing wanted criminals
and unscrupulous Hunters.
富と名声 これこそ　ハンターの魅力だ！
The fame and money... That's why people wish to become Hunters!
深遠な知識と健全な心身 強い信念！
Profound knowledge, a healthy mind and body, and unyielding conviction...
それこそが　ハンターの誇りだ！
Those are the qualities on which
Hunters pride themselves!
ゴン！　お前は　どうなんだ？ ゴン！　お前は　どうなんだ？
Gon! What do you think?
どっちのハンターを目指す!? どっちのハンターを目指す!?
Which kind of Hunter do you
hope to become?!
「どっち」っていわれてもなぁ…。
Well, when you put it that way...
着いたらしいな。
I think we've arrived.
話の続きは　後だ。 はぁ。
We'll continue this later.
何か　異様な雰囲気だぜ。
Strange atmosphere down here.
港や町にいたハンター志望者とは 明らかに違う。
They clearly differ from the
Hunter applicants we saw at the port and in the city.
全員が何らかの達人に違いない。
Each is a master, in their own right...
あの…。
Excuse me...
何か　みんな　ピリピリしてるね。
Everyone's really tense.
どうぞ 番号札をお取りください。 あぁ…。
Hello. Please take a number.
はい　どうぞ！
Here you go.
はい。
Here.
必ず胸につけ　紛失されませぬよう よろしくお願いいたします。
Be sure you wear this on
your chest at all times. Be careful not to lose it.
君達　新顔だな？ ん？
Haven't seen you guys around before.
よぉ。
Yo.
俺達のこと　分かるの？ まぁね。
You can tell we're new?
よっと。
More or less.
何しろ　俺　もう３５回も テスト受けてるから。
After all, this will be my thirty-fifth attempt.
３５回!?
Thirty-five times?!
まぁ　試験の ベテランってわけだよ。
Well, you could say I'm an exam veteran.
威張れることじゃねえよな。
That isn't something to brag about.
確かに。
Indeed.
分からないことがあったら 何でも聞いてくれ。
If you have any questions,
feel free to ask me.
ありがとう。 俺は　トンパってんだ！
Thank you. My name is Tonpa.
俺は　ゴン。
I'm Gon.
こっちは クラピカとレオリオだよ。
These are Kurapika and Leorio.
ねぇ　トンパさんみたいに
Hey, are there others who
何度も試験を受けている人って 他にもいるの？
have taken the exam a bunch
of times like you?
まぁ　俺ほどの ベテランは　いないが そうだな…　例えば　あいつ。
Well, I have the most experience here, but there are a few others. For instance, there's him...
パワーは断トツだな 意外と頭も切れる。
He's unmatched in strength. And he's smarter than he looks.
その向こうにいる １０３番の蛇使いバーボン。
On the other side, we have number 103, Bourbon, the snake charmer.
あいつは非常に執念深いから 敵に回すと厄介だぜ。
He tends to hold grudges, so you don't want to end up on his bad side.
それから… １９１番　武術家のボドロ。
And then... Number 191, Bodoro,
the kung fu master.
年は　とっているが 武術において右に出る者なし！
He's getting old, but there still isn't
a better martial artist around.
あいつらは アモリ　イモリ　ウモリの３兄弟。
Then you have the three brothers,
Amori, Imori, and Umori.
絶妙なコンビプレーで 常に好成績を挙げている。
They perform consistently well, thanks to their excellent teamwork.
そして３８４番　猟師のゲレタ 吹き矢と　こん棒で
And number 384, Gerreta,
the huntsman. He specializes in killing
あらゆる生き物を仕留める スゴ腕だ。
all manner of creatures,
by blow dart and club.
まぁ　他にもいるが このあたりが常連だな。
There are many more, but they have taken the test
the most times.
へぇ。
Ah...
あら　不思議。
Oh, how peculiar...
腕が花びらとなって 消えちゃった。
His arms seem to have become flower petals.
種も仕掛けもございません。
No smoke and mirrors here.
気をつけようね。
Do take care.
ひとに　ぶつかったら 謝らなくちゃ。
When you bump into someone,
you really should apologize.
ヤバい奴が　今年も来やがった。
That psychopath is back again.
「今年も」？
Again?
ということは　去年もいたのか？
Does that mean he took last year's exam?
４４番　奇術師ヒソカ。
Number 44. Hisoka, the magician.
気に入らない試験官を 半殺しにした奴だ。
Last year, he was a virtual
lock to pass the test, until he all but killed an examiner he didn't like.
そんな奴が　今年も堂々と テストを受けられるのかよ？
A-And they're still allowing him to
retake the exam this year?
当然さ　試験官もテスト内容も 毎年　変わるし テスト内容は　試験官が決める。
Of course. Every year, the examiners and
test content change, and the examiners are the ones
who choose the new content.
それがハンター試験さ。
The devil himself could pass if that were
the examiners' determination. That's just how the Hunter Exam works.
とにかく 奴は　みんなから嫌われている。
Anyway, no one likes him.
近づかねえほうが　いいぜ。
You should stay away, too.
確かに　ヤバそうな奴だ。
He looks dangerous.
That much is for sure.
んっ　そうだ！
Oh, right...
お　こいつは　ありがたい！
How about it? Oh, appreciated.
ちょうど喉が　渇いてたんだよ。
As it happened, I was thirsty...
ありがとう！
Thanks!
どうも。
Thank you.
ククク…　始まった。
There he goes.
親切面しやがって 自分が一番タチ悪いくせによ
He always plays the nice guy, despite being nastier than
anyone else here.
新人つぶしのトンパ
Tonpa, the rookie crusher...
じゃ　お互いの健闘を祈って カンパイ！
Best of luck to all of us!
ヒヒヒ…　お前らに渡した そのジュースは 超強力下剤入り
The juice I gave you contains an
extremely strong laxative.
ひと口　飲めば　３日は 腹が　ノンストップ　ジェットコースターだ！
One sip, and for three days, your guts will be a non-stop roller coaster.
お前らは　もう　オムツしなきゃ テストを受けられねえぜ ヘヘヘ…　ヘヘヘヘ…
You'll need diapers to take the exam.
トンパさん　このジュース 古くなってるよ？　味が変！
Tonpa-san, this juice must have expired. It tastes funny.
マジか！　危ねぇ！
Seriously? That was close!
あっ　あれ？　おっかしいなぁ。
H-Huh? That's strange...
バカな！　あの下剤は　ほとんど 味も　においもしないはず
Impossible! That laxative should have
practically no taste nor scent.
申し訳ない！
I'm very sorry!
古いのがあるなんて 気づかなかったんだ！
I didn't realize the juice had gone bad.
いいよ　そんなに謝らなくて。
It's okay. You don't have to apologize.
トンパさんは　お腹　大丈夫？
Is your stomach okay?
ん…　ああ　平気　平気。
Y-Yes... I'm fine.
俺　山とかで　いろんな草や芽を 試し食いしてるから
I've sampled all kinds of mountain
grasses and plants.
大体　味で変なものが分かるんだ！
So I can usually taste when something's bad.
そっ　そうなんだ ハハ　すごいね　そりゃ…。
R-Really? That's amazing...
クソ　とんだ野性児だぜ…
Damn... I had to run into
this wild mountain kid.
悪かったな　んじゃ　また…。
Sorry about that again. I'll see you around.
騒がしい　おっさんだな。
Talkative old man...
それにしても　一体全体 今年の新人は どうなってるんだ？
Still, there's something wrong
with this year's rookies.
あの２９４番の ハンゾーって奴も
That number 294, Hanzo, too.
声かけた時は　すぐ騙せそうな 奴だと思ったんだが
He seemed gullible when I approached him.
((ここだけの話 俺　忍者なんだよ))
Don't tell anyone else, but I'm actually a ninja.
)
Huh? Oh, really?
I seek the legendary scroll... Shh...
((「最強忍者の書」って巻物を 探し出すために ハンターになりてぇんだ))
The Ultimate Ninja Scroll.
That is why I desire to become a Hunter.
((どうやら　一般庶民じゃ 入れねえ場所に
I've heard that it's hidden somewhere
隠されてるらしいんでなぁ))
inaccessible to ordinary people.
((しっかし 辛気くせぇとこだよなぁ))
Anyway, it's boring here...
((まぁな　あぁ　それより　どうだ？ お近づきの印に))
Yeah, I guess... So, how about it? Let's toast our new friendship.
((忍びの習性でな
As a ninja, I make it a point
ひとから　もらった飲食物は 喉を通らねえんだ))
to never drink anything someone else offers.
)
Sorry.
I-I see...
あの目　ただ者じゃ　ねえ
I could tell by his eyes that he's no fool.
うかつに手を出すと こっちが危ねぇ
One false step, and I could've
been in real danger.
危ねぇといえば あの３０１番
Speaking of danger, there's number 301...
あいつに至っては 雰囲気がヤバ過ぎて 声すら　かけられねえ
That guy just oozes peril.
I can't even go near him.
それよりも気に入らねえのは あいつだ １８７番　ニコル
Then there's that guy I can't stand, number 187, Nicolas.
((ここに　たどり着くまで 大変だったろ？))
Must've been tough to make it here.
((いいえ　僕の予想した データ通りでしたね))
Not really. Everything went
as predicted by my data...
((ハンター試験の 過去のデータから 今年の試験会場を 割り出しておいたんです))
I used historical data, from past Hunter Exams,
to calculate this year's location.
((実に簡単ですよ 物足りないくらいだ))
Quite simple. Frankly, I was bored senseless.
((そ　そうか そいつは　すげぇな))
R-Really... That's amazing.
)
My name is Tonpa. Nice to meet you.
Tonpa-san, is it?
)
Oh, there you are.
) )
This is your thirty-fifth attempt, the second-highest number by one person.
((そのうち　本試験連続出場３０回は 断トツの１位))
And with thirty, you have the most
consecutive appearances.
) )
Very impressive. Please, it's no big deal.
)
How about it?
Let's drink to our new friendship...
((だが　その本試験においては なかなか 合格できずにいらっしゃる))
But you have yet to actually pass the exam.
((それは　別の目的に
I assume that's because
気をとられ過ぎてるからでは ないですか？))
you're too absorbed by your other objective.
)
Eh?
Tonpa-san, the rookie crusher.
)
What?
((まぁ　このことは 他言しないでおきますよ)) ((連続出場記録保持者の 顔を立てて))
Well, I won't share my knowledge
with anyone else, seeing as you hold the consecutive
appearance record...
)
Goodbye.
あの野郎　見てろよ
Bastard... Just you wait.
その生意気な鼻 すぐに　へし折ってやる
I'll break that snotty nose of yours.
さっきのジュース　もっとくれる？
Could I have more of that juice?
緊張してんのかな… 喉　渇いちゃって。
Must be my nerves. I'm really thirsty.
え!?　あぁ　いいぜ。
Eh? Oh, sure...
こいつ　さっき飲んだ下剤が もう　とっくに効いてるはず
What the hell? The laxative he drank earlier should
have taken effect by now.
どうなってやがんだ？
What's going on?
いくら下剤とはいえ これだけ飲めば 脱水症状　起こして 死んでも　おかしくは　ねえ
It's only a laxative, but if he imbibes that much,
he could die of dehydration.
心配？ え？
Worried?
俺なら平気だよ　鍛えてるから。
I'll be fine. I've trained.
毒じゃ死なない。
Poisons won't affect me.
「毒」!?
Poisons?
こいつ　ジュースの中身を 分かっていたのか
He knew what was in the juice?
分かってて　それでも平気で 飲んだってぇのか!?
But he still drank it?
９９番　キルア
Number 99, Killua.
とんでもねえぜ 今年の新人達はよ…
This year's rookies are all insane...
フン！ まぁ　いい
Well, it doesn't matter.
それだけ　つぶしがいが あるってもんだ
That just means crushing them will
be all the more worthwhile.
大変お待たせいたしました。
I apologize for the wait.
ただ今をもって ハンター受験者の受付時間を 終了いたします。
The entry period for
Hunter applicants has ended.
では　これより ハンター試験を開始いたします！
The Hunter Exam will now begin!
最終確認です。
A final caution.
実力が乏しかったりすると 大ケガをし
If you are short on luck or ability, you could very well end up
最悪　死に至ることもあります。
seriously injured or even dead.
それでも構わないという方のみ 私に　ついて来てください。
Those who accept the risks,
please follow me.
そうでない方は 後ろのエレベーターから 速やかに　お帰りください。
Otherwise, please exit via
the elevator behind you.
第１次試験４０４名
All 404 applicants will participate in Phase One.
やっぱり　誰一人　帰らねえな ちょっとだけ期待したんだが。
Of course, no one turned around and left. I'd hoped a few might withdraw.
な…　何だ？
Wh-What?
前のほうが走りだしたんだよ。
The people in front started running.
先頭がペースを上げたんだ。
He's picked up the pace.
申し遅れましたが
I neglected to introduce myself.
私　第１次試験　試験官の サトツと申します。
I am Satotz, the Phase One examiner.
これより　皆様を ２次試験会場へ案内いたします。
I shall lead you to the exam's Second Phase.
２次？　…ってことは　１次は？
Second Phase? What about Phase One?
もう始まっているのでございます。
It has already commenced.
始まってるのかよ これが試験？
It's already begun? This is part of the test?
「２次試験会場まで 私に　ついて来ること」。
You must follow me to Phase Two.
これが１次試験でございます。
This is the exam's First Phase.
ついてく？ ただ　ついてくだけか？
Follow you? That's it?
はい　場所や到着時刻は お答えできません。
Yes. I cannot tell you where or
when you must arrive.
ただ　ついて来ていただきます。
You need to follow me.
なるほどな。 変なテストだね。
I see how it is. This test is weird.
さしずめ　持久力試験ってことか。
I expect it's an endurance test.
望むところだぜ！ どこまでも　ついてってやらぁ！
Fine by me. I'll be right behind you!
だが　どこまで走ればいいのか 分からないのは
But there is the mental stress
of not knowing
かなり心理的負荷となる
how far we'll have to run.
精神力も 同時に試されるわけだな
He's also testing our mental fortitude.
つわもの　くせ者が ひしめく中 第１次試験開始
The exam's First Phase begins, amidst a mix of warriors and knaves.
スタート前に１名脱落し
One candidate is disqualified
before it even starts.
ハンター受験者は　総勢４０４名
The total number of Hunter
applicants is 404.